Burd-Shippen Papers 1708-1792 Mss.B.B892
American Philosophical Society
- Correspondence, 1740-1792; Series I; 1 lin. foot
  - to James Burd, 1760 September 9; 1p.; Gibson, James (Box 3)
    Bushy Run. Notice of John Wion deserting.
  - to James Burd, 1760 November 6; 1p.; Hannah, James (Box 3)
    Carlisle. Request for pay.
  - to James Hamilton, 1760 November 19; 2pp.; Armstrong, John (Box 3)
    Carlisle. Complaints have been made to Commissioner of Indian trade. Only trying to get line for Shamokin-Susquehannah land agreeable with Treaty of Albany. Should not listen to silly complaints of Indians. Freeman and Smith 2709.
  - to James Burd, 1760 December 1; 2pp.; Johnston & Graydon (Box 3)
    Fort Augusta. Situation at garrison, note on unresolved issue regarding men who will not re-enlist, informs him on the state of his room, and as when he will arrive.
  - to Caleb Graydon, 1760 December 19; 1p.; Johnston, Francis (Box 3)
    Fort Augusta. Request for pay.
  - to James Hamilton, 1761 February 23; 1p.; Shippen, Edward (Box 3)
    Receipt for marriage and tavern licenses issued in Lancaster.
  - to James Burd, 1761 May 6; 1p.; Ourry, Lewis, 1717-1779 (Box Oversize)
    Carlisle. Issuing a new receipt for payment.
  - to James Burd, 1761 May 21; 1p.; Little, John (Box 3)
    Carlisle. Still lacking supplies, inquires when he will receive them.
  - to James Young, 1761 June 25; 1p.; Graydon, Caleb (Box 3)
  - to Mrs. Burd (?), 1761 July 18; 1p.; Hunter, Samuel (Box 3)
    Fort Hunter. Received sheep for Fort Augusta.
  - to "Madam" (Mrs. Burd?), 1761 August 2; 1p.; Hunter, Samuel (Box 3)
    Fort Hunter. Notice has received cattle for Fort Augusta.
  - to James Burd, 1761 August 26; 1p.; Graydon & Hunter (Box 3)
    Fort Augusta. Note regarding cattle.
  - to John Cameron, 1761 August 12; 1p.; Wister, Daniel (Box 3)
    Philadelphia. Regarding purchase of cloth.
  - to James Burd, 1761 September 10 and 15; 2pp.; Graydon, Caleb (Box 3)
    Fort Augusta. Informs him of the supplies received, and inquires about his return should the paymaster arrive. Notes death of his brother.
  - to James Burd, 1761 October 13; 1p.; Bouquet, Col. (Box 3)
    Fort Pitt. Acknowledges receiving letter.
  - to Edward Shippen, 1761 November 5; 2pp. [fragment]; Hunter, Samuel (Box 3)
    Fort Augusta. Mentions that only a few Indians are trading. Also contains note from Edward Shippen to Sarah Burd. Freeman and Smith 2763.
  - to unknown, 1761 November 13; 1p.; Graydon, Caleb (Box 3)
    Fort Augusta. Went to Philadelphia on business regarding death of his brother, has sent copies of letters from the governor (not included). Notes supplies at fort.
  - to James Burd, 1761 November 27; 2pp.; Shippen, Edward (Box 3)
    Lancaster. Informs him of the birth of his daughter, and has obtained a warrant for his land.
  - to Sarah Burd, 1761 December 2; 1p.; Hunter, Samuel (Box 3)
    Acknowledges receipt of items.
  - to James Burd, 1762 January 31; 1p. [parts faded]; Willis, Jonathan (Box 3)
    Philadelphia. Regarding a license to trade with the Indians.
  - to James Burd, 1762 February 11; 2pp.; Young, James (Box 3)
    Philadelphia. Comments on settling account, advice on roll of men for pay, news of assembly in Philadelphia.
  - to Unknown, 1762 July 13; 2pp.; Irvine, James (Box OS)
    Complains of illegal trade in liquor to the Indians. Indian evidence unacceptable and there is no other. Dennis McCormick, Burd's storekeeper [at Fort Augusta] got Sushocapee drunk. Freeman and Smith 2765.
  - Affidavit, 1762 July 17; 1p.; McCormick, Dennis (Box 3)
    Lancaster. Claims he never sold liquor to Indians, but gave an Indian woman a pint of rum. Freeman and Smith 2886.
  - to James Burd, 1762 July 29; 1p.; Young, James (Box 3)
    Philadelphia. Obtained warrant as asked, will bring pay for men, comments on heat in Philadelphia.
  - James Irvine, 1762 July; 1p.; Brown, Joseph (Box Oversize)
    States that Dennis McCormick did sell liquor to the squaws. Freeman and Smith 2874.
  - to unknown, 1762 August 6; 1p.; McCormick, Dennis (Box 3)
    Fort Augusta. Sending articles.
  - to James Burd, 1762 September 25; 2pp.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia. Concerning trade goods and treaty for Indians. Sends belt of wampum and must know state of mind of Indians. Freeman and Smith 2744.
  - to unknown, 1762 October 10; 2pp.; Burd, James and Josiah F. Davenport (Box 3)
    Pittsburgh. Have arrived with goods for Indians. Seeking release of prisoners. Shawanees slow in arriving, hit by disease. Quarrel over order with Colonel Bouquet. Freeman and Smith 2720.
  - to John Shaw, 1762 December 11; 1p.; Smith, William (Box 3)
    Request for material to make a shirt.
  - to James Burd, 1762 December 25; 1p.; Graydon, Caleb (Box 3)
    Fort Augusta. Inquires about news. Comments on garrison.
  - to James Burd, 1763 January 10; 1p.; Davenport, Josiah (Box 3)
    Fort Pitt. Cover letter for sending letter from governor.
  - to James Hamilton, 1763 January 12; 2pp.; Shippen, Edward and Thomas Barton (Box 3)
    Lancaster. Acknowledgement of patronage of the Library Company of Lancaster, and request for making it a corporate body.
  - to unknown, 1763 February 25; 2pp.; unknown, Daniel Stiss, and Jacob Willsohn (Box 3)
    [letter difficult to read].
  - to James Hamilton, 1763 April 12; 3pp.; Shippen, Edward (Box Oversize)
    Lancaster. Regarding the building of new mills and damns on Conestoga Creek.
  - to James Burd, 1763 May 10; 2pp.; Powell, John (Box 3)
    Bill for schooling.
  - to James Hamilton, 1763 June 10; 2pp.; Ourry, Lewis, 1717-1779 (Box 3)
    Fort Bedford. Surrounding farmers have volunteered for service, and will remain if taken under provincial service.
  - to James Hamilton, 1763 June 29; 2pp.; Ourry, Lewis, 1717-1779 (Box 3)
    Fort Bedford. Comments on the conduct of the inhabitants during the recent insurrection.
  - to James Hamilton, 1763 July 20; 2pp.; Ourry, Lewis, 1717-1779 (Box 3)
    Fort Bedford. Situation of the harvest during the insurrection.
  - to Edward Shippen and James Wright, 1763 July 23; 1p.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia. Instructions to investigate the killing of two Indians to determine if the gentleman had cause.
  - to James Burd, 1763 July 23; 1p.; Hunter, Samuel (Box 3)
    Fort Hunter. Left side of letter missing.
  - to James Hamilton, 1763 August 2; 4pp.; Ourry, Lewis, 1717-1779 (Box 3)
    Fort Bedford. Situation at the post concerning the commissioning of volunteers and protecting reapers.
  - to Edward Shippen, 1763 August 10; 1p.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia. Gives reward of £30 to man who killed three Indians. Freeman and Smith 2747.
  - to James Hamilton, 1763 August 10; 2pp.; Ourry, Lewis, 1717-1779 (Box 3)
    Fort Bedford. Mentions Indian attack near Ligonier. Freeman and Smith 2811.
  - to James Young, 1763 August 23; 3pp.; Hamilton, James and Commissioners (Box 3)
    Philadelphia. Instructions for paying troops on the frontier.
  - to James Hamilton, 1763 August 26; 3pp.; Ourry, Lewis, 1717-1779 (Box 3)
    Fort Bedford. Problem of unlicensed taverns, and need for a magistrate.
  - to James Hamilton, 1763 September 1; 3pp.; Shipped, Edward (Box 3)
    Lancaster. Describes Indian battle at Murray Hill. Freeman and Smith 2846.
  - to James Hamilton, 1763 September 6; 2pp.; Ourry, Lewis, 1717-1779 (Box 3)
    Fort Bedford. Comments on Paul Vaugh's petition.
  - to James Hamilton, 1763 October 6; 1p.; Shippen, Edward and Thomas Barton (Box 3)
    Lancaster. Regarding the charter of incorporation for the Library Company, and the naming of the library.
  - to James Hamilton, 1763 October 12; 3pp.; Ourry, Lewis, 1717-1779 (Box 3)
    Fort Bedford. Continued problem with unlicensed taverns and liquor, conditions facing his replacement regarding the inhabitants and Indians.
  - to Edward Shippen, 1763 October 13; 1p.; McCormick, Dennis (Box 3)
    Fort Augusta. Explination for two bills.
  - to James Burd, 1763 November 3; 1p.; Blyth, William (Box 3)
    Fort Auguta. Request for pay.
  - to James Hamilton, 1763 November 11; 1p.; Shippen, Edward (Box 3)
    List of payments for tavern licenses.
  - to James Burd, 1764 April 20; 1p.; Ranberry, Henry (Box 4)
    Request for discharge.
  - to James Burd, 1764 June 19; 1p.; McCormick, Dennis (Box 4)
    Arrived with cattle, waiting for escort.
  - to James Burd, 1764 November 28; 2pp.; McCormick, Dennis (Box 4)
    Fort Hunter. Selling of hides, notice more troops arriving at Fort Augusta and need of provisions.
  - Affidavit, 1764 December 13; 1p.; Bissit, Thomas (Box 4)
    Lancaster County. Testimony regarding a dispute between two men at the Cornwall Iron Works.
  - to James Burd, 1765 May 31; 1p. [fragments missing]; Gibson, John (Box 4)
    Philadelphia. Note regarding shipment.
  - to James Hamilton, 1765 May; 1p.; Webb, James (Box 4)
    Account for wood sold for use in soldiers' barracks.
  - to John Gibson, 1766 February 26; 1p.; Burd, James (Box 4)
    Lancaster. Question about debt Burd owes the province.
  - to James Burd, 1766 April 7; 1p.; Wilkins, John (Box 4)
    Carlisle. Request for certain provisions.
  - to unknown, 1766 July 17; 1p.; Smith, James (Box 4)
    Relates to the lack of action being taken against offenders who attacked Mr. Simpson.
  - to James Burd, 1766 December 6; 1p.; Fulton, Robert (Box 4)
    Lancaster. Regarding payment due court.
  - to unknown, 1767 January 8; 1p.; J. D. (Box 4)
    Post script to letter, list of books to be given to Mr. Davidson, bookseller.
  - to James Burd, 1767 March 2; 1p.; Hunter, Alexander (Box 4)
    Fort Hunter. Inquires if Burd would marry a young couple.
  - to James Burd, 1767 September 1; 1p.; Harris, John, 1726-1791 (Box 4)
    Paxton. Unable to travel to Philadelphia as family is ill. Comments on reports about him.
  - to Edward Shippen, 1767 November 15; 1p.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783 (Box 4)
    Philadelphia. Return from England after illness, and looks forward to seeing Shippen.
  - to James Burd, 1767 December 7; 1p.; Gellson, William et al. (Box 4)
    Lancaster. Certification of Geroge Gibbson's ownership of land.
  - to James Burd, 1767 December 18; 1p.; McClure, Richard (Box 4)
    Request for road to be built as approved near Fisher Creek.
  - to James Burd, 1768 January 22; 1p.; Atlee, William (Box 4)
    Lancaster. Relates to court matters in sale of property, congradulates Burd on birth of son.
  - to Edward Shippen, 1768 May 12; 1p.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783 (Box Oversize)
    Philadelphia. Happy to hear of Shippen's improved health, can not journey to Lancaster.
  - to James Burd, 1768 May 30; 1p.; Clark, William (Box 4)
    Issue of traps.
  - to James Burd, 1768 August 12; 1p.; Harris, Johhn (Box 4)
    Paxton. Sending boards left after others taken, and the flood.
  - to Robert Dicks and James Welsh, 1768 September 9; 1p.; Burd, James (Box 4)
    Lancaster. Matter of a mare and damage to the fence of Lawrence McGill.
  - to James Burd, 1769 February 14; 2pp.; Peters, Edward (Box 4)
    Philadelphia. Matter regarding property.
  - to James Burd, 1769 March 11; 2pp.; Burd, Edward (Box 4)
    Philadelphia. Note on family's health, Dutch servant, and ability to visit pending business of the court.
  - to James Burd, 1770 June 30; 1p.; Atlee, Samuel John, 1739-1786 (Box 4)
    Informing him of a decision on a matter.
  - to James Burd, 1770 August 24; 1p.; Shippen, Edward (Box 4)
    Lancaster. Cover letter for material regarding the purchase of land near Jonathan Harris.
  - to James Burd, 1770 October 3; 1p.; Harris, John, 1726-1791 (Box 4)
    Paxton. Request to borrow equipment.
  - to James Burd, 1770 November 7; 1p. [fragments missing]; Dougherty, Dennis (Box 4)
    Carlisle. Settling matters with Peter Dougherty and Cornelius Ryan.
  - to James Burd, 1771 May 17; 1p.; McMurray, James (Box 4)
    Lissburn. Work on an ax.
  - to James Burd, 1771 November 15; 1p.; Bickham, James (Box 4)
    Sending salmon.
  - to James Burd, 1772 March 5; 1p.; Davis, Henry (Box 4)
    Requests pass for Richard O'Neal.
  - to Sampson Sadlie, 1772 May 21; 1p.; Burd, James (Box 4)
    Lease agreement to Sampson Sadlie for house on Burd's Tinian plantation.
  - to William Plunket, 1772 June 25; 1p,; Forster, Thomas Jr. (Box 4)
    Upper Paxton. Notice he will pay debt once Simpson sells land on the Delaware and pays him.
  - to James Burd, 1772 August 18; 1p.; McCall, James (Box 4)
    Asks for note given Burd in 1768 regarding a debt with Samuel Crawford.
  - to James Burd, 1773 March 5; 1p.; McClenachan, James (Box 4)
    Inquires about verification of land purchase from Mr. Shippen.
  - to James Burd, 1773 December 29; 1P.; Boyd, Robert (Box 4)
    Wishes to settle accounts, comments on his health, and asks Burd's assistance in settling account with Mrs. Wells.
  - to James Burd, 1774 April 15; 1p.; Illing, Frederick (Box 4)
    Middleton. Receipt for marriage license to Abraham Gross.
  - to James Burd, 1774 September 15; 2pp.; Burd, Edward (Box 4)
    Reading. Mentions his purchase of land, and the possibility of the people putting Ross out of the Assembly.
  - to James Burd, 1775 July 7; 1p.; Grant, Ann (Box 4)
    Fort Augusta. Asks assistance in getting account paid from Lewis Lewes, even if the law has to be used.
  - to James Hamilton, 1777 February 22; 2pp.; Shippen, Edward (Box 4)
    Lancaster. Copy of letter from January 30 regarding use of timber at barracks, which was Shippen's last letter; along with a letter regarding the use of additional timber to build a stable for the Contiental horses. [Originally cataloged under January 30 date].
  - to James Hamilton, 1777 March 13; 1p.; Shippen, Edward (Box 4)
    Lancaster. Settling of account for use of timber for stockade.
  - to Edward Shippen, 1777 April 28; 1p.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783 (Box 4)
    Philadelphia. Expresses to Shippen his views of settling accounts using Continental Money over Pounds Sterling, and related instructions to Shippen on accounts.
  - to James Hamilton, 1777 June 2; 2pp.; Shippen, Edward (Box 4)
    Lancaster. Copy of letter informing Hamilton of additional use of the timber on his land.
  - to Edward Shippen, 1777 July 1; 2pp.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783 (Box 4)
    Philadelphia. Reply to June 2 letter, commenting on unauthorized use of his land, and his inability to travel by act of the Assembly.
  - to James Burd, 1779 February 11; 1p.; Galbreath, Major, et al. (Box 4)
    Invitation for Burd and his family to attend a dance.
  - to James Burd, 1780 November 12; 1p.; Burd, Edward (Box 4)
    Sends state money to help pay taxes, comments on when he can visit.
  - to James Burd, 1785 July 4; 1p.; Gregg, A. (Box 4)
    Middletown. Delivery of late note from Mr. Temple and asks for answer.
  - to James Burd, 1785 October 25; 2pp. [fragments missing]; Burd, Joseph (Box 4)
    Carlisle. Comments on seeing brother, and getting new shoes.
  - to Hugh Curry, 1786 December 1; 2pp.; Burd, James (Box 4)
    Lease agreement for land in Paxton.
  - to James Burd, 1788 July 23; 1p.; Fulton, Henry (Box 4)
    Asking to give son his horse.
  - to Joseph Shippen, 1788 October 6; 1p.; Butler, Anthony (Box 4)
    Philadelphia. Inquiry for account information of the governors of Pennsylvania for five years in order to get compensation from Great Britian.
  - to John Penn, 1788 November 1; 4pp.; Shippen, Joseph Jr. (Box 4)
    Lancaster. Replies to Penn's request for an accounting of fees and Emoluments collected five years prior to the Revolution. Inventory of account included [was originally cataloged separately under 1771-1776].
  - Affidavit, 1788 November 1; 1p.; Shippen, Joseph Jr. (Box 4)
    Affidavit for Joseph Shippen, Jr. being secretary of the colony, and to the information in the Inventory of Fees and Emoluments for the Government of Pennsylvania.
  - to Phineas Bond, 1788 November 2; 1p.; Shippen, Joseph Jr. (Box 4)
    Lancaster. Informing him he has completed the account of Fees and Emoluments as requested.
  - to Joseph Shippen, Jr.., 1788 November 7; 1p.; Bond, Phineas, 1749-1815 (Box 4)
    Philadelphia. Thanks Shippen for the affidavit and inventory. Comments on the compensation to Proprietors..
  - to Phineas Bond, 1788 November 10; 2pp.; Shippen, Joseph Jr. (Box 4)
    Lancaster. Reply to question of how fees were accounted.
  - to James Burd, 1792 October 28; 1p.; Pattesron, George (Box 4)
    Patterson Mills. Friendly note, comments on new mill, and future visit.
  - to James Burd, May 24; 1p.; Jameson, David (Box 4)
    York. Cover letter for return of recruits (not included0.
  - to James Burd (?), June 14; 1p.; Clayton, Alexander (Box 4)
    Philadelphia. Asks for George to come help him, and comments on his arriving at Fort Augusta.
  - to "Madame ma tres chere et honoree Mere ...", n.d.; 1p.; Corne, B. (Box 4)
    [letter in French].
  - to James Burd, n.d.; 1p.; Currie, Johnn (Box 4)
    Regarding Ashton's intention to leave.
  - to Richard Peeters, n.d.; 2pp.; Dunlop, William (Box 4)
    Regarding a dispute over land ownership between William Dunlop and Thomas Trindlery.
  - to James Burd, n.d.; 1p.; Fulton, Robert (Box 4)
    Request to recover expenses.
  - to James Burd, n.d.; 1p.; Graydon, Caleb (Box 4)
    Settlement of account.
  - to Joseph Armstrong, n.d.; 1p.; McConnell, Robert et al. (Box 4)
    Petition for his assistance in matter.
  - to James Burd, n.d.; 1p.; McCormick, Widow (Box 4)
    Regarding summons to court.
  - to unknown, n.d.; 1p.; Orndt, Robert (Box 4)
    Thank you for money sent.
  - to Arthru Sinclair and Archibald McClean, 2pp.; Unknown (Box 4)
    Instructions for the survey of Western Pennsylvania.
  - to Mr. Taffe, n.d.; 1p.; Saller, E. (Box 4)
    John Sacalamus wants Indian trade goods. Freeman and Smith 2843.
  - to William Allen, n.d.; 1p.; Tilghman, James (Box 4)
    Reference to Thomas Parson's health, and the Penn-Connecticut controversy. [see note from WJB].
- Legal and Financial, 1708-1791, Undated; Series II
  - Bills protested by James Logan for non-payment, 1708 August 25 - 1709 July 29; 3pp.; Logan, Jim, (James) (Box 5)
    Protest letters for bills unpaid.
  - Account with Alexander Stupart., 1748 July 14; 1p.; Burd, James (Box 5)
    Listing of account.
  - Bill of sale to James Burd, 1747 April 29; 1p.; Lumley and Ray, Grocers. (Box 5)
    London. For purchase of candy.
  - Invoice for James Burd, 1748 August 3; 1p.; Coningham & Gardner (Box 5)
    Philadelphia. Invoice for linen purchased.
  - Bill of Exchange to James Burd, 1748 October 15; 1p.; Coningham & Gardner (Box 5)
    Philadelphia. Invoice for payment.
  - Statement to Jonathan Evans, 1749 February - July; 1p.; Burd, James (Box 5)
    Statement of account.
  - Account with James Burd, 1749 March 23; 1p.; Branson, Willi (Box 5)
    Account for "Shott."
  - List of goods sold, 1749 June 1; 2pp.; Burd, James (Box 5)
    List of goods sold since 1749 June 1.
  - Invoice of goods shipped to London, 1749 July 20; 1p. (Box 5)
    .
  - Bill of sale to James Burd, 1749 August 3; 1p.; Coningham & Gardner (Box 5)
    Philadelphia. Bill of sale for canvas.
  - Bill of exchange to Johannes Kern, 1749 December 29; 2pp.; Barkley, Thomas (Box 5)
    Maryland. Bill of exchange and copy.
  - Bill of exchange drawn on James Burd, 1749 December 29; 2pp.; Barkley, Thomas (Box 5)
  - Account Books, 1749; 29pp. [fragmentary condition]; Burd, James (Box 5)
  - Statement to William White, 1749; 1p.; Burd, James (Box 5)
    Account statement for damask.
  - Invoice of wine shipped by James Burd, 1750; 1p. (Box 5)
    Invoice for items shipped aboard the Mary Humphry Class for Barbadoes.
  - Statement of goods put on the snow, Sally, at risque of James Burd and Alexander Hamilton, 1750; 1p. (Box 5)
    List of items shipped.
  - Bill of exchange drawn on James Burd, 1749 -1750 January 1; 1p.; Barkley, Thomas (Box 5)
    Bill of exchange.
  - Bill of exchange drawn on James Burd, 1750 January 3; 1p.; Barkley, Thomas (Box 5)
  - Bill of exchange drawn on James Burd, 1750 January 5; 1p.; Barkley, Thomas (Box 5)
  - Account of James Burd, 1750 January 13; 1p.; Dunnings, James (Box 5)
    Account statement for meals, rum, etc.
  - Bill of sale to Perry Ward, 1749/50 March 23; 1p.; Burd, James (Box 5)
    Invoice for "Stript to bind."
  - Statement of accounts to James Burd, 1750 March 30; 1p.; Carter & Stout (Box 5)
    Statement of account for building the snow, Sally, with dimensions of vessel.
  - Statement of accounts, 1750 April 20; 1p.; Evans, Simon (Box 5)
    Invoice for work at his house [plastering, etc.].
  - Copy of cargo of the Sea Horse, 1750 May 30; 4pp.; Peters, William (Box 5)
    Items shipped in the brigantine Sea Horse.
  - Invoice to James Burd, 1750 June 25; 1p.; Forbes, Alexander (Box 5)
    Invoice of Brazil Wood.
  - Invoice of goods shipped at risque of James Burd, 1750 July; 1p. (Box 5)
    Items shipped aboard the vessel Maulesfield including wine and wood.
  - Memorandum to George McKnight, 1750 November 3; 1p.; Philip, Robert (Box 5)
    Informing James Burd of carpenter and sailor for hire and cost.
  - Invoice of wine shipped, 1750 November 20; 1p.; Burd, James (Box 5)
    Items shipped aboard the brigantine Endeavour.
  - Order to James Burd for payment, 1750 November 21; 1p.; Graydon, Alexander (Box 5)
    Order to pay for certain supplies.
  - Account of laborers and victuals on board the snow, Sally, 1750 December 8; 1p.; Philip, Robert (Box 5)
    Accounting of bread and beef to laborers.
  - Bill of exchange drawn on James Burd, 1750/51 January 1; 1p.; Mitchelson, George (Box 5)
    Maryland. Bil of exchange.
  - Statement of account of James Burd, 1750/51 March 15; 1p.; Steel, Robert (Box 5)
    Account for £250.
  - for Edward Shippen, 1755; 1p.; Burd, James (Box OS)
    Memorandum of agreement with George Croghan.
  - Account of expenses of cutting a road, 1755 April 1-9; 1p.; Burd, James (Box 5)
    Road to Auchwick via Alloqueepys Town across the Juniatto to Sugartree Hill. Freeman and Smith 2873.
  - Statement of accounts with Adam Hoops, 1755 April 23; 1p.; Burd, James (Box 5)
    Account of items purchased.
  - Statement of accounts to George Croghan,... James Burd, 1755 April 25; 1p.; Cummings, John (Box 5)
    Account for wine.
  - Advertisement for workmen to work on the road, 1755 May; 1p.; Buchanan, William (Box 5)
    Specifies what the men should bring, and where to meet.
  - Statement of accounts to James Burd, 1755 June 28; 1p.; Packwood, Samuel (Box 5)
    Statement of account for feeding certain men.
  - Account with James Burd for work on the road, 1755; 2pp.; Barr, John (Box 5)
    Listing of various expenes building the road.
  - Cash advanced to laborers, cutting the road, 1755; 1p.; Hoops, Adam (Box 5)
    List of workmen and pay.
  - Memorandum to Joseph Burd that Dominick Mannin lost an ax, and his account., 1755; 1p. (Box 5)
    List of account.
  - Order to pay William Gibson, 1756 March 24; 1p.; Morrow, Robert (Box 5)
  - Promissory note to James Burd..., 1756 April 24; 1p.; Turner, John (Box 5)
    Promissory note for provisions.
  - Agreement between Jannett Pypper, and John Pypper, 1756 May 21; 4pp. [fragments missing]; Burd, James (Box OS)
    Agreement for renting Burd's plantation in Shippensburg. Includes account of farm utensils left.
  - Promissory note to James Burd, 1756 September 4; 1p.; Hays, Thomas (Box 5)
    Fort Augusta. Agreement to pay upon order.
  - Statement of accounts, receipted to James Burd, for silk, buttons..., 1756 November; 1p.; Bickham, James (Box 5)
    List of items billed.
  - Account with the Province of Pensilvania [sic] for horses, hay, etc., 1756 December 1; 1p.; Hunter, Samuel (Box 5)
    Account invoice.
  - Statement of accounts with Major Burd for rum, breakfast ..., 1756; 1p.; Frapnell & Taffe (Box 5)
    Itemized list.